오늘밤, 제임스는 칠판에 그림을 그립니다.
제임스는 사람한테 손을 흔들구요
저는 식탁으로 부터 도망칩니다.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
안녕하세요, 모두들 안녕하세요 환영합니다.
감사합니다. 정말 감사합니다.
저는 종종 질문을 받습니다. 그러니까, 가끔 질문을 받는데
데
그러니까 사실, 어떤 사람한테 질문을 받은적이 있는데
왜 저희가 톱기어에서 복스홀을 자주 리뷰 하지 않는가에 대해서 말이죠.
대답은 간단합니다. 복스홀은 존나 쓰래기거든요.
하지만 복스홀에서 신형 아스트라를 내놓았는데
요번건 쓰래기가 아니라는군요
흠........
이차이름은 VXR이고 제원상으로 만보면 명백한 개쓰래기 차입니다.
Because what they've done,
bless them, is fit under the bonnet
of a front-wheel drive
Vauxhall Astra,
a 276 horsepower engine.
That's as daft as fitting the heart-
of an elephant in a mouse.
The thing is, the front wheels
have to do the steering
and that's a big, important job.
And asking them
to handle 276 horsepower as well,
means you've to do some
very, very clever engineering.
Not that long ago,
Vauxhall was making the not-at-all
cleverly engineered Vectra.
The most dreary, uninspiring
car in all of human history.
Oh!
It really was a cure for ADD.
If you put a hyperactive child
in there, he'd be asleep
in three minutes flat.
I mean, look at it!
It's as gripping
as a Victorian novel,
as stylish as a taxman's trousers.
You almost got the impression
they designed it in a coffee break.
Oh, quick, the boss wants
a new car. There's one.
Give it some fancy door mirrors.
It'll look like we made
an effort. They hadn't!
So the idea that a company
which did this,
now thinks it has the technical
ability to put 276 horsepowers
through the front wheels of
a hatchback is laughable.
The thing is though, amazingly,
they've pulled it off!
It has a clever front diff
and unlike a normal Astra,
it has hydraulic power steering.
It also has the same
sort of dampers that Ferrari use
and James tells me
it has separate hub carriers.
Which is interesting!
Plainly then, they've spent more
time and effort on the front end
of this car, than they did
on the whole of the Vectra.
And the rewards are huge.
There's no torque steer,
there is no fuss, there is no drama,
the power is just there
when you want it.
It might not be the most fun
car in the world,
it actually feels quite heavy,
but, my God, it is quick!
And best of all, despite extremely
wide low-profile tyres,
it has a comfortable ride as well.
If you like being uncomfortable,
you can push this sport button here-
which firms everything up
and if you want to feel like you're-
falling down a rocky escarpment,
you can push this one.
If you do that, watch, ready...
look, all the dials glow red
to warn you that your neck
is about to snap.
Probably better to leave
those buttons alone, clearly.
This is a damn good car. It's solid,
good looking and very, very fast.
Plus, because it's a hatchback,
it's practical as well.
There are, as I see it,
only two problems.
One - at just shy of ￡27,000,
it is quite expensive.
And two - when you are asked at
parties what you're driving
these days, you're going to have
to start by saying... erm...
Perhaps then, we should look
at the Astra's chief rival -
the Ford Focus ST.
This has five doors, so it is more
practical than the Vauxhall.
It's ￡5,000 cheaper and at parties,
you can say you own a Ford
without blushing.
But it simply isn't
as nice to drive.
Instead of taming the front end
with proper mechanical
engineering like Vauxhall did,
Ford has used electronic systems
and the truth is,
they're not as good.
You can sense the electrons
doing their absolute best to
keep things neat and tidy,
but you can also sense them, erm...
failing!
There's torque steer,
there's understeer,
and then there's
lift off oversteer.
There.
It is a smorgasbord of waywardness.
I also have to say the Ford has
a particularly unpleasant interior.
And it does not look very
good from the outside either.
Nowhere near as good as the Astra,
that's for sure.
So, as an enthusiast's car, I have
to say the Vauxhall is better.
But this is Top Gear
and I can't very well sit here
and say, "Hey, petrol heads,
the best hot hatchback
is a Vauxhall Astra."
That would be like a travel person
saying, "Hey, holidaymakers,
"the best place for your
summer vacation is Belgium!"
So, let's keep going
and look at another option.
The Renault Megane 265.
This is the darling
of all the car magazines.
They love it
and it's easy to see why.
You can just tell this car was
designed by a team of people
who really know what enthusiasts
want when they're on the track.
It's sublime.
They've even fitted it with a
special readout that shows how fast
you went from 0 to 60,
how fast you did the standing
quarter, your lap times,
how much power you're using,
how much brake you're using,
your throttle position, a graph,
an extreme graph,
your G metre.
The Stig just loves this.
He's been running around all
morning squawking
and clutching at his tinkle!
And I have too, if I'm honest!
It's just an amazing combination
of nimbleness and brute force.
There's no doubt that it's more
exciting than the Vauxhall
and less wayward than the Ford
and faster than both of them.
To show you how much faster,
I engaged sport mode
and pulled up for a drag race.
Watch and learn, Vauxhall!
What?
Come on!
Come on! Faster!
Come on-n-n-n!
That was not supposed to happen.
Much to my surprise then,
the Renault was the slowest.
And when you bear
equipment levels in mind,
it is the most expensive, too.
And it's also the least nice.
Sitting in here is a bit like
sitting in Eeyore's gloomy place,
it is all very dark and everything
you touch and everything you use
feels flimsy, like it will come off-
or break at any moment.
And the back's very cramped
and the ride's very hard,
this seat is very low down
and very snug
and gives you an idea of what
it would be like to be buried alive.
And look at this. You can't wear
a pink shirt or it'll clash.
So, while this may be
the nicest car
to drive on a track or
a deserted moorland road,
it would not be the nicest to live
with on a day-to-day basis.
That means we arrive at a rather
worrying conclusion because,
if I were to choose one of these
three cars to drive home in tonight,
it would be...
the...
What happened there?
The camera broke. Did it?
Yeah, no, it literally just broke
there. Did it?
And what were you about to say?
Erm, I can't remember.
You were about to say the Vauxhall.
A bit.
It's a surprisingly likeable car.
It just is.
Isn't that a bit like saying
Piers Morgan is a surprisingly
likeable man, but in the end,
he is still fundamentally
Piers Morgan, isn't he? Awful man.
Yes, I know what you mean.
Look, hold on a minute.
The Ford is ￡5,000 cheaper,
it is the most practical, with
the most doors and we've just seen
it is the fastest. I'd have that.
There's a lot to commend the Ford.
You're right. I like the Renault.
Oh God! This is brilliant
buyers' advice, isn't it?
I'd have the Ford,
you'd have the Renault,
and he'd have the Piers Morgan. I
know how we can sort this out.
The tame racing driver.
Some say he contains 47% horse.
And that to concentrate
more on his work here,
he's resigned, this week,
from his other job in Rome.
All we know is,
he's called The Stig!
'And they're off.
Sluggish start from the Ford.
'But it soon bites
'and finds its stride on the way to-
the first corner.
'And it's the Renault
looking twitchy into there,
'the other two nicely controlled
and gripping hard.'
'The Stig still listening to
national anthems
'and a cacophony of patriotic noise.
'All tracking cleanly around
Chicago
'now spooling up the turbos
for the run to Hammerhead,
'hard on the brakes, might see
something mealier from the Focus.
'But no. Almost threatening
to cock a back wheel.
'And the Renault just scampers away-
like a cheese-crazed sport monkey.'
'Wow! A stack of Stigs there.
Follow-through.
'The Focus is getting out of shape,
'quickly pulls it back
together again.
'Quick through the tyres, two
corners left, the Vauxhall appears
'to be composed,
the Renault looking
bumpy on the way in.
'It's the most track-ready car here.
Here they come, up to Gambon.
'No dramas at all
and across the line.'
I have the times here
and they are not that fast.
The Ford Focus did it in 1.29.6.
The Vauxhall Astra did a 1.28.3
and the Renault Megane,
the most track-focused of them all, -
did a 1.27.7.
So therefore, the conclusion is,
if you want a relatively
inexpensive, fun car,
buy the Toyota GT 86!
We're really not much good at that
consumer advice thing, are we?
Anyway, we must now do the news.
Yes, and it's bad news!
Dacia have got their name wrong.
Have you seen the car ads
they've been doing?
They keep referring to
themselves as Datcha.
I think that's because
that's how you say it in Romania,
where it's built.
There's another labelling
problem they've got,
because I was reading up
on the new Sandero.
It says it's got 90 horsepower.
With everything
that's been going on,
how do we know that isn't cow
power?
Yeah. Good point.
Because those abattoirs are in
Romania,
allegedly. Apparently.
We went to Romania once
and we did see a lot of people
riding around on cows,
rounding up horses.
And all their farmers complaining
about getting up early
to milk the horses! Exactly.
So, it is a 90 cow power car,
we've established now. Good.
On the show, we've always said you
can't be a proper petrolhead
until you've owned an Alfa,
which has always been
an embarrassing problem for me,
because I haven't.
But that might be about to change
with this, the Alfa Romeo 4C.
A little two seater,
1.8 litre turbocharged engine
mounted in the middle,
chassis made of carbon fibre.
At least it won't rust.
They'll find a way.
They'll have bought cheap Russian
carbon fibre that somehow oxidises.
You know what Alfa's like!
How much is it?
It's going to cost between
40 and 50,000.
I have a bit of a problem with that.
I don't think the looks are quite
right. Eh? It's gorgeous.
I think it's a bit too tall.
Exactly. It is.
I'll tell you how it does look good-
though, is if you see the plan view.
We've got one of those.
Now that, I think, is good.
That's a view Hammond will never
have! Oh, come on. Please!
Haa-haa! Open door. Yeah, all right.
Now the Ford Mustang we featured
last week in the race across Europe,
that seems to have captured
the hearts and minds of everybody,
I mean, really.
Everywhere I've been, all week,
people have been talking to me
about that car. Yeah, non-stop.
Well, big news.
Ford has announced, because they've-
never sold the Mustang
officially in Britain, since 1964,
they've announced that the
next generation of Mustang
coming next year, will be
built with right-hand drive
and will be sold in Britain.
About time, brilliant, good news.
There is, however,
a tiny bit of bad news. What?
Well, the V8 version will be
sold in America, but,
because we're only British,
all we can have is a two litre
eco-boost engine.
Oh, for God's sake!
Do they think we want that?
I can't understand their logic.
If you want a Mustang,
it is because
you want a big V8 muscle car,
there is no other reason
for buying one. Precisely.
So if you want a two litre
eco-boost car,
you are going to buy a Golf diesel.-
Not a Mustang.
It's like saying
I formed a punk band,
we got cellos, except for Sebastian,
he has a harp.
Nobody wants a harp in a punk band,
nobody wants a two litre eco-boost
engine in a bloody Mustang.
You can keep it, we don't want it.
Just keep it. Keep them.
Now, the most important
news of the week.
As you may have noticed,
modern cars now have been given
electronic handbrakes, rather than
a lever. This is a problem,
because you can't do a handbrake
turn with an electronic button.
And this is bad news,
because handbrake turns are an
essential part of male development,
because as we all know,
the handbrake lever is connected
directly to a girl's sexual
appetite!
It is. It is. When you're 17, it is.
You're smiling and you know it is.
You see it in the animal kingdom.
A peacock has his feathers.
The young man has his handbrake.
Exactly. They do the same job.
And if you have a button,
it doesn't work. No.
I can remember my first attempt
at seduction with the handbrake
when I was 17 years old.
I was going to pick up this girl
called Liz from outside a pub
and I had it all planned.
I'd go in and I'd get on
the handbrake and slew it round
like the Italian Job and the
rest was a formality, obviously.
I went through the gate, quite hot, -
pulled on the lever and that was
when the cable snapped.
I think it was because I had spent
the previous day practising,
you see... Only you would
practise a
handbrake turn! You have to.
Wish I had. What? I remember taking-
a girl called Cathy home one night.
I was 17, in my mum's Audi.
And she lived in the middle
of a field and I do mean
in the middle of a field,
no tracks, anything.
Was she called Ermintrude?
Did she wear a nice big bell? No,
she wasn't a cow! Moo. Or a horse.
No, no.
Anyway, I am going down the grassy
hill, to the house and thought,
I know what will tip her
over the edge. Brrt!
Pirouetted straight through her
dad's hedge. Was she impressed?
I know she was,
because she pulled a
face that was exactly like this.
That's the face,
that's the face they pull
in that part of the mating ritual.
I know,
because I have seen that face.
When I was a young man, 17,
borrowing my dad's car,
diesel Astra estate,
and I was giving Katie from college
a lift home, she lived on a farm,
down farm tracks and I had already
warmed her up
with a bit of rally driving!
There was already
a sexual tension in the car.
And I thought, "I'll seal the deal
with the handbrake lever,"
yanked it on, slewed round, hit a
rock. She pulled that exact face.
What, the...? Sometimes girls say,
"What did you do that for?"
That's it. What they're actually
saying is, "I'm ready!"
But I never got that face from Liz, -
because as far she was concerned,
she didn't know I had tried to do a-
handbrake turn, because
I had just got that twang, that was-
the only twang I got
on that evening!
As far as she could see,
I had just parked badly
the wrong way round.
She just thought I was an cars. I
think I know why they're doing this.
It's to cut down on unwanted
teenage pregnancy.
And it could work.
It's a clever thought.
It'll probably work, but it'll also-
cut down on the future of mankind.
I think it is irresponsible.
If you think about it,
if a man can't use a handbrake to
pull a girl, what's he going to do?
There's going to be
a lot of frustrated men around.
You may have to talk to her.
No! No! Car makers, please, stop it.
You're meddling with forces unseen
and more powerful than you.
Shall we get back to cars?
Yeah, let's do it.
Peugeot, as we know, are
the worst driven cars on the road,
always doing 40 in the outside lane,
they're always in your way.
But now there is a new car from
Peugeot. We have it here
in the studio. It's called the Onyx.
It looks absolutely fantastic
and you'll notice that some
of the bodywork is made from copper.
Just like the boiler tubes
on a Greeley A4 Streamliner Pacific.
Yes, James, yes, yes.
And it's actually untreated copper, -
so over time, it'll turn green
unless a scrap metal merchant
removes it in the night.
Inside they've continued
the theme of
using unusual materials,
so the dashboard is made out of
recycled newspaper.
I'm guessing they'll have used
the Guardian for everything
on the left and the Telegraph
for everything on the right!
Actually the newspaper is good
because it means there is no need to
Bluetooth your phone to it.
The dashboard will already have
listened to your messages for you.
The engine is 680 horsepower
V8 turbo diesel hybrid.
That means a top speed
in the outside lane of 40.
Anyway, this is the future, perhaps,
but now we must return to
the present, because we have some
important information.
The Kia Cee'd, which we use
as our reasonably priced car
has been updated and the new
version
is taking the world by storm.
This is it.
It has only
been on sale for eight months
and already it has won the coveted
Northern Car Of The Year award.
A chap called Derek Grocock
who is vice chairman of the
Northern
Group Of Motoring Writers
said it had impressed the judges
with its comfort, value,
reliability, quality,
and its seven-year warranty.
But this is Top Gear
and we are interested in,
all of that obviously,
but rather more besides.
So now let's see how well
it does at
all the things that matter to us.
Of course there is only one man
we can turn to for an answer.
Matt LeBlanc,
the fastest star we have ever
had in our reasonably priced car.
Of course Matt lives in Los Angeles
but he appreciated
the importance of the question.
First, the old car.
Old versus new.
The age-old question.
And now, the new version.
Ah, that new-car smell. Huh?
So there we are.
Thanks a lot. Thank you. Any time.
With Matt gone I moved on to a test-
I could handle myself.
I'm coming up now
to a row of parked
cars in a top-of-the-range Cee'd
which has this
little button down here.
If I push it, sensors start to scan-
the gaps to see if any of them
are big enough for me to park in.
What about this gap here?
I don't think that's big enough.
Does the car agree?
It will "bong" if it thinks
it's big
enough. It didn't like that.
What about this one?
There it is.
Now that's very impressive.
But what
it does next is even better.
If I put it in reverse
I am told this will go into that
gap
with no steering input
at all from me.
To see if that is true
I am going to wear a blindfold. OK.
I can now see nothing at all.
Here we go.
Easing it backwards. Hands not
on the wheel. Oh, my God,
it's turning.
This is spooky.
I'm going to get some beeps
to tell me when
I'm close to the car behind.
There we are.
Then I put it in drive.
This...
This is weird now.
If I take this off and I am parked
I shall be amazed.
So now let's consider some rather
more important questions.
Yes.
We plugged the lead into
the auxiliary socket
and asked a local
guitarist to try it out.
He seemed quite impressed.
So far then the little Kia
is passing all our tests
and passing them well,
but I know what you're thinking.
This is a big problem because
if you have your container of water
for the eel
and even a small amount of sodium -
I've only got 100 grams here -
and the two were to
come into contact with one another, -
the results could be catastrophic.
As I shall now demonstrate.
Time and time again we hear
about eel and sodium salesmen
going about their business
when all of a sudden...
their car explodes.
To make sure that doesn't happen
in the Cee'd, special segregated
trays are fitted underneath
the boot floor
so you can have your sodium
in one tray,
separated from the water into which-
I am now going to place an eel.
There we go. Don't jiggle about.
You'll get water on the sodium.
That's what happened to your mum.
Stay. Good eel. Excellent.
Now we will just close
the boot floor.
That really is an intelligent
piece of design.
So now let's look at another vital
issue that was not
addressed by Mr Grocock.
Yes, he can.
And he managed to do that
without getting any more
blood or oil on his shirt.
Yes it is. A mid-range 1.6 litre
Kia is 17,195. A mid-range 1.6
litre Focus, 17,200.
For the price of the Focus
you can have a Kia
plus ￡5 to spend on...
￡5 worth of things.
There was a time when Kias
were cheaper than their European
rivals because they were very nasty,
but those days have gone.
This really is not nasty at all.
I think it is
good looking on the outside,
good looking on the inside as well.
It has sophisticated independent
rear suspension
so you can stick it into a corner
pretty confident that you
will come out OK on the other side.
It is well-equipped.
And it has passed nearly all
of our tests with flying colours.
The Kia Cee'd - good enough
for Mr Grocock and good enough
for Top Gear.
Very thorough. Very, very thorough.
A lot of information there.
A lot of important information.
Yes, absolutely,
but for me the most impressive thing-
was that parking system. I know.
That is uncanny.
Although I should say in fairness
you can also get that
system on Fords and Volkswagens
and Toyotas these days.
Yes, anyway, between you
and Mr Grocock, Eric Clapton...
Brue Willis...
and Matt LeBlanc, that is the Kia
completely covered.
No, not quite,
because there is one more important-
question we have to deal with.
Is there?
Is it, "Can a badger drive it?"
That is a good idea, but no.
It is, "Can you play rugby in it?"
Rugby?
Yes, rugby. If you are watching
in America, rugby is
a bit like American football
only it's played by men.
And you are going to try
and play it in a car?
Yes, it is one of the most
ambitious
things we have ever attempted and
we will see how it does later on.
Now, though, it is time to put
a star in our reasonably priced car.
My guest tonight is a young
chap from Hertfordshire
who recently got a new Mercedes
and wants to come and tell us
all about it. Normally
we would tell him to get lost.
But we decided to make
an exception on this occasion
because...
his name, ladies and gentlemen,
is Lewis Hamilton.
Great! You are back. You are back.
Good to see you.
Lewis is among us.
Have a seat. Have a seat.
It feels good to be back. Luxury.
Obviously the first question
is the big one.
You have moved from McLaren
to Mercedes.
Is that not a bit like moving
from Manchester United to West Ham?
Firstly, thanks for
the warm welcome, everyone.
Don't change the subject.
Good to be back.
Yes, no, it's a big change for me
obviously,
but I'm really excited about it.
Everyone is criticising it and
has their own opinions but for me
I have been at McLaren
since I was 13.
It was a long period there and I
wanted a change. I am a risk taker.
There is a risk and a risk because
McLaren have won, what, 182 races.
Mercedes has won... one in five
years. What makes you think...?
Well, they won the Championship.
Well, it was actually Brawn...
Brawn. Technically not...
Have they told you that? "We've won.
We've won." You are right.
They have struggled
the last few years, but I think
when the rules came out in 2009,
everyone came out with
the design of a car and
they started out, and every year
after that it is an evolution of
that car.
And they started off on the wrong
foot and they've been on the wrong
foot since then.
One of the things I thought,
you had to do a lot of PR
work at McLaren, didn't you? Mm.
Everybody knows that is dreadful.
Yeah.
"Buy this terrible thing that
sponsors our car."
Is there going to be less of that?
A lot less, yes. A lot less? Yes.
That is good enough. Why did you
not just say because you have
to do less
standing around talking rubbish?
It's not that.
There were so many good
things about the opportunity to go
somewhere where they are struggling-
and hopefully be
a part of something that will get
somewhere and become great.
Michael did it years ago
with Ferrari.
No other driver has done that
really, so I want to do
something like that.
So we needn't expect to see you
leading everybody around
from pole position?
You definitely should not
expect that this year.
Because initial testing has not
been
completely successful so far? No.
It wasn't good. Brake failure on my-
14th lap. What speed? Pretty fast.
Yeah. I was at the end of the back
straight going into turn six
and hit the brakes at 180 mph, 190,-
and then nothing happened.
I just went straight in...
So when you
put your foot on the brake pedal
and you're going 180 and nothing
happens. Poo?
No, you do swear though. You have
time to think of a swear word?
Yes, you do.
And you have time to brace. Do you?
Yes, so I was going
towards the wall and
I remember just holding on for dear-
life knowing it was going to hurt.
Did it hurt? It did.
Particularly in my legs.
For some reason, I don't know,
I went in straight ahead,
but my legs seem to hurt
when I go straight into a wall.
Now, I do know what
I need to talk to you about.
The handbrake in the modern car.
Have you ever thought, "If I pull
this, she...?" I am sure I have.
In the first years that
I was driving, I'm sure.
We were discussing this earlier.
It is one of the weirdest things.
We are all fairly clear,
girls don't like men who do
handbrake turns, but we think
they do. My girlfriend loves it.
Does she? I have a good
story about my handbrake turns.
Years ago I was at a karting race
in Italy with Nico as my team mate.
It was 2000.
Me, my dad and Keke Rosberg,
were on our way to the track
and my dad was driving down this
country lane, which off the edge
of the road drops down into a field
and there is a metre drop.
Keke all of a sudden just pulls the-
handbrake while my dad is driving.
And my dad doesn't really know
how to drive that well.
He thinks he's a great driver...
He's not here to argue.
Lost the back end of the car
and put it down into the ditch
and we had to leave it there
and walk to the track.
There wasn't even a girl
in the car?
Who was Keke trying to impress?
I don't know. Your dad.
My dad, yes. Keke is gay!
And on that bombshell...
Now, I know that you have been
very much looking forward to
coming back here. Yes, I have. You
have been here before. Yes, 2008.
Now most guests do a lap,
take the weather on the chin,
snow, ice, rain, and then go
away. You did not do that.
You were cross, weren't you?
I was not happy that it was raining.
It was wet. I am told that you
took our producer around the back...
and a deal was done
that you could
come back and try again
when the track was dry. Yes.
This was a bloody quick time. 1.44.
And it was wet. Wet and oily.
Oily, was it? Get it right. Yes.
Racing drivers' excuses, but...
I thought wet was all it said,
but it's wet and oily.
Wet and oily, you said.
You said someone in the last
corner dumped some oil.
It had come out of Hammond's hair.
Obviously, thorn in your side here, -
Sebastian sits at the top.
That irritates you? Mm-hm.
He's had the best car
for God knows how many years
and is also the quickest on Top
Gear, so... You wanted to come
and do something about that?
Every driver wants...
I remember when Rubens
came and did the time.
We went to a drivers' briefing
in Germany. He brought everyone
a shirt.
He gave himself, "I beat The Stig"
and everyone else
"The Stig beat me."
So you didn't do your lap today?
No.
You came down
and did the lap many months ago.
Who would like to see Lewis
practising for his lap?
Yes
Let's have a look.
There he goes.
Second to last corner
catches all of our guests out,
including one Lewis Hamilton.
Was that me? Yes.
I only put it on to make all
the other guests feel better
because they are like,
"No, I have spun off."
Now they can go, "At least
Lewis Hamilton did exactly the same-
thing in exactly the same place."
Nevertheless, you then lined up
to do your lap again.
- Who here would like to see it?
- Yes.
Here we go.
It is, of course, the old Liana.
That was a good gear change.
Come on, baby!
Yes, we do not use
the Cee'd for Formula One drivers.
You all have to drive that.
It's nice to see it back looking
tall and ungainly and slow.
'I thought you were determined
to go fastest?'
'I was.' 'Singing. It's like Kimi
Raikkonen looking at the planes.'
Whoo!
'Look where you're going.
'Is this the sort of man who looks
like he's determined
'to go faster than
Sebastian Vettel?'
'Look at that, I didn't even
cut the
corner.' 'I'm very impressed.'
Not surprised,
but I'm very impressed.
'Here we go.'
'That was to the cameraman.'
'I know.'
'That was close to the tyres.'
'A couple of bites at the cherry.
That's nicely done.'
'It actually looks like it handles
quite well, bless it.' 'It does.'
'And there we are, everyone,
across the line.'
There is no point asking you where
you want to come. You know.
You know where you want to be.
Well, Lewis Hamilton. Mm-mm.
It was a 1.44 that Sebastian did.
Lewis Hamilton, you did it in...
one...
42.
Unbelievable.
Unbelievably fast time.
Wa-hey!
I will leave it there.
You weren't even concentrating.
Wow. Holy crap. Pleased?
I'm really surprised.
It didn't even look like you
were concentrating. I was.
It has been months and
you guys wouldn't even tell me.
No, we never tell anybody.
I was thinking to myself,
"I'm going
to be so disappointed in myself
"if I didn't do
a competitive time."
Anyway, he has now hung himself.
And obviously everybody here
is very pleased to have a Brit
back on the top of the leaderboard.-
Yes.
When I say everybody, there is one
man who is not pleased. The Stig.
He knew about this time
months ago when you did the lap.
This week he left the country.
He went to North Korea to do
an experiment. We don't know what.
So apart from him
everyone is thrilled.
Ladies and gentlemen, the fastest
man we've ever had - Lewis Hamilton.
Well done, mate.
That was worth coming back for.
Without a doubt.
Now, a couple of weeks back
we finished our American road trip
at the Mexican border.
The last one there had to cross over-
and test something called
the Mastretta, which is a new
sports car being made there.
Now, Top Gear is not
very popular in Mexico
because of some comments
that were made on the show.
And, unfortunately,
the man who lost that race,
and would therefore have to
go into Mexico
and test the Mastretta was
the man who made those comments -
our Director of
International Relations,
Boutros Boutros Hammond.
OK, so, here we are in Mexico
but it's all right,
I have everything under control.
You see?
An angry Mexican looks in,
they'll see Jeremy,
and they hate Jeremy
just as much as they hate me.
Look at me!
Power! Oh, everything's rubbish.
Except, no, cos I am now Jeremy,
so they'll still cut my head off
and then...
I haven't thought this through
at all, have I?
I'm not going to bother with that.
OK, let's get this test over with
as quickly as possible
and get out of here.
'Eventually, I found a place
where no-one could see me
'and I could get on with some
serious road testing.'
So, what have we got here?
Well, its full name
is the Mastretta MXT
and this is the first
fully home-grown Mexican car.
'Now, when most countries
make their first car,
'it's something cheap
and practical for the masses.
'But what the Mexicans have done
is skip the intro
'and gone straight for a sports
car.'
Any similarities between this and an-
early Lotus Elise are not accidental.
It's small, it's compact,
leather bucket seats,
suede-ish trim here and there.
Steering wheel no bigger than
a tortilla, which is a good thing.
'The interior, the chassis
and the body are all Mexican made.
'But the 2.0 litre turbo engine
is actually from over the border.'
It's a Ford and it makes 250bhp,
enough to take the Mastretta
to 60 in 4.9 seconds.
Which could be useful if, say,
somebody was trying to chase you.
'Unlike some lightweight sports cars,
'the Mastretta offers luxuries
such as air-con and a stereo.'
Put the radio on.
Oh, yeah, my favourite. I love this.
'Despite the equipment,
the MXT is no fatty -
'weighing in at just 1,050 kilograms
'thanks to a chassis made
of carbon fibre and aluminium.'
You can see how
they've tried to keep
all the car's weight
between the wheels,
which is why there is absolutely
no overhang at the back or the front,
which is all well and good,
still not
sure about the styling, though.
It looks like an Audi TT
that has been squashed in a vice
and that's a good thing.
Very good. Morning!
Buenos dias.
The kind of thing Ferrari
could learn
a lot from. I shouldn't sit on it,
I don't want to scratch it.
Look at that - sleek.
Yeah!
'The really good thing
about the Mastretta
'is that it pretty much does
what it says on the tin.'
For a simple, uncomplicated,
little, track-day car,
you want it to feel like a go-kart.
This kind of does.
It does grip.
I was waiting for understeer then,
there wasn't any.
The gear linkage, always difficult
when the engine is behind you,
works very well.
'But it's not without faults.'
The bonnet rattles about a bit.
The windscreen wipers
occasionally set off
for a wander
all on their own without being asked.
The seals around the windows
are terrible, hence the noise.
And it makes a hell of a noise
over the bumps,
of which there are a few in Mexico.
'At ￡37,000, it's also nearly
ten grand more than a Lotus Elise.
'And, unfortunately for me,
the fuel tank is small.'
Hola. Petrolo pumpo numero uno,
por favor.
'Despite the flaws, inside
the Mastretta is a good little car,
'just waiting to be finished.'
The thing is, we have kind of
been here before in a way.
James and Jeremy,
when they went to China,
and it wasn't brilliant.
First attempts never are but,
and who knows, with more time
and more practice,
one day the name Mastretta
might really stand for something.
I think, on the whole,
that went pretty well.
That car's been behind me
for a while
now. He's following, isn't he?
That is... He's... He's following me.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know. Really?! Really?
What? Were you just being nice
so you weren't beheaded?
No, no, like I said, it is
genuinely quite a good little car.
Once they sort out some quality
issues it shows real promise.
Well, listen,
the hatchet is now buried, OK?
I think, thanks to Ban Ki-Hammond,
we can now move on
because, tonight,
we are subjecting the new Kia
Cee'd to many, many thorough tests.
And coming up now is the most
thorough test of them all.
Can you play rugby in it?
'Since we were being thorough, we
didn't bother with some minor
league
'club ground but headed instead
for the home of English rugby...'
'..Twickenham.'
OK, I'm going to be captaining
the grey team and the silver team
will be captained by a man who
knows this ground incredibly well.
He drives past it almost
every day. James. Jeremy.
Rules of car rugby. Yeah, and I've
got a question straightaway.
Which is?
On behalf of the viewers, I suspect,
don't you have to pass it
backwards?
In real rugby, yes. That's not
possible. So, we're not doing that?
Are we allowed to do this?
What, here? Yes. Yes!
Has anybody said
"hallowed ground" yet? Not yet.
Can if you want. Go on then.
On this hallowed ground,
we are about to play car rugby.
'In our game, the Cee'd
will be the speedy backs.
'And up front, we'll be using
Kia Sportages as the hard men -
'the forwards.
'So, all we need now is a ref.'
OK, are you ready, James May?
Yes. I'd just point out that
the referee can't speak
and he doesn't know the rules.
But, yes, I'm ready.
'As team captains, Clarkson and I
were both in cars numbered four.
And punt!
Yes! They're reversing.
Look, I'm frightening them!
Argh! I've lost it.
Forwards, forwards.
Here we go. May is ready
to go through the gap. Yes!
Oh, it's still mine.
No, I've lost it.
Oh, look at this.
He's carrying it!
He's picked up the ball
and he's running with it.
'Bravely, James tried to
block my beefy forward.'
I think we can get this back.
Oh!
Well done, men. Well done!
I'm loving your play.
'Then, grey five broke free.'
Yes, I'm here and ready.
Yes! Yes!
Yes! No!
Yes!
Ye-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-e-es!
What a try!
Whoo-hah!
'Having established the Cee'd
could score a try,
'it was now time to see
if it could do the next bit.'
OK, time for a conversion.
Why does he do that?
Why does Jonny Wilkinson do this?
Right, here we go.
At Twickenham!
Yes!
No, no, no, no!
Rubbish.
Fall in, grey.
Come on, winger! Come on!
I should explain,
James May is using a diesel,
it has a higher top speed
than my 1.6 litre petrol
but I have better acceleration,
less weight.
Oh, no, this is bad. They're free.
Come on, winger.
Winger. Winger.
Nice play, guys. Nice play.
Ooh! Violent move there.
Must be James.
And was.
Keep it in. Keep it in
A-ha! It's gone out.
I think you'll find that's a grey
throw-in. What's a grey throw-in?
This is a grey car. No, but your
bloke knocked that out. He didn't!
He did! He didn't.
I'm going to go and ask the ref.
Whose throw-in was that?
Silver? Grey? Can you point?
The worst referee I've ever
come across.
I told James the ref had said it
was a grey throw-in.
So now it's time
for our first lineout.
This is a very useful
feature of the Cee'd.
It's small, compact,
so you can get a good run-up
for taking a lineout.
Here we go.
And... a bit of wheel-spin and punt!
Oh, push, push, push!
I'm against the bigger man... car!
Use that torque!
Ah, they're only front-wheel drive, -
those Sportages,
but they have power.
Come on, team!
Where's the ball gone? There it is.
James had the ball
and was heading for the try line.
Dribbling...
What's it called in rugby?
Running with it.
But we soon put a stop to that.
Ooh! Oh!
So now,
my grey team had the advantage.
Go, number 5. Go, go, go, go!
Ain't no stopping him now!
He's on the move.
He's in the groove!
Yes!
Come on, number three!
That is a try.
This is hopeless.
We're getting thrashed at this.
Weirdly, my team let me
have another go at a conversion.
Right, I'm going for a massive,
massive, massive, kick this time.
Go over!
Yes! Yes!
It's a big
oooooooooooooooooooooone!
At this point,
the ref signalled half-time.
And, in the dressing rooms,
we had the obligatory team talks.
Right, chaps, we are fine athletes, -
I think anyone can see that.
But there is a lot we can
learn from actual rugby players.
This was drawn up
for a recent match they played
and this is what I want you to
concentrate on in the second half -
mindset, go for it, enjoy it,
never give in, OK?
And I think we can add a fourth
to that, which is ram James May.
OK?
Ram him whenever you see him
and ram him hard.
Really hard.
Gentleman, I don't want to put
too fine a point on this.
It's half-time, we're losing,
you're a bit crap.
Now, when we're on the attack
we're getting very messy.
Go up the pitch together
in formation,
so we can pass straight up but be
ready to come back down again.
Very important,
reversing if necessary.
If not, you can get to the other
end
and you can quite easily do
a handbrake turn around the post.
Either side,
handbrake turn around the post,
up you go again to the top and kill-
Clarkson. That's all you have to do.
Any questions?
'We knew, as the second half began, -
we had it all to do.'
Right, my blokes need to
get in there and batter them.
'The lads did just that.'
'And soon I got a break.'
It's a run!
I'm coming in from the back!
I know that's Clarkson
trying to tackle me.
Yes!
That's a try!
Oh, my God!
'Naturally, I elected
to take the conversion.'
Please miss. Please miss.
Oh, he's done it!
Give me that!
Damn it!
'May's comeback wasn't
the only problem.'
Oh dear, this hallowed turf is
starting to get
a bit messed up, if I'm honest.
'And things really weren't helped
by the scrums.'
Oh no, it's... I'm stuck.
I've dug a big hole. I can't get...
But on the upside, everything
was lovely inside the Kias.
You see, normally when people play
rugby they get hot
and they get sweaty but we're not
having any of that here.
Got the air conditioning set just
so. I'm not hot, I'm sitting down.
'Whilst I was distracted by the Kia,
Team May broke through again.'
We're on the run.
Stop him, somebody!
This is what we want!
Here we go.
That's a try!
Beautiful!
'Worse still, James got a second
successful conversion.'
Yes!
'Putting his team ahead.'
They are destroying us
in this phase of play.
'With just two points in it
'and the rain turning
Twickenham's hallowed turf
'into a muddy skating rink,
'the play became dirty...
'and violent.'
Classic rugby weather.
I must say, viewers,
at this point I have no idea what
Jeremy has said in this test.
I can confirm, though, that
the Cee'd crashes quite well.
Coming in for a try...
Boof!
Ooh, crikey, Moses!
These things are built
like brick lavatories.
'Which was good,
'because on this surface stopping
was becoming a bit of an issue.'
'Football, that we used to play,
car football...'
Ooh, chit!
'..Is well-suited to a...'
Sorry. That was a total mistake.
My fault.
That's not cricket.
It's actually not that bad.
It'll buff out.
'Despite some injuries,
'all the Kias were still playing as-
the match entered its final phase.'
Oh, he's on a run!
Oh, come on, men!
Pass it.
Don't try and get through. Pass.
No!
It's us! It's us! Go, go, go!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Looking good!
Oh, don't back up!
Go!
Yes! That is a try!
Read it and weep!
I think we've learned
two things tonight.
Number one,
if you want to play rugby in a car,
the Cee'd is brilliant.
It's fast, it's agile
and it's tough.
But, perhaps more importantly,
we've learned that grass
is not a good surface.
I mean, we've only played
one match here and look,
the pitch is completely ruined -
absolutely ruined.
They're going to
have to pave this over, really.
Hold on!
Hold on.
Chaps?! What?
Do you know why they call it
hallowed turf?
Erm...
Because it is hallowed.
Do you know what hallowed means?
Temporary.
Yes, yes, James. "Our Father who art-
in heaven, temporary be thy name."
Oh, yeah. I do think we owe
everyone
a apology. Yes, you do.
Because we've just shown strong
pornography before the watershed.
Sorry, what?
All that handbrake action.
Oh, yes.
Every single girl watching tonight
will be cross-eyed.
Good point. They don't see
two fat middle-aged men any more.
What they see are Bradley Cooper
and Ryan Reynolds.
I'm not sure the handbrake lever
is that effective. Yes, it is.
And on that bombshell,
it is time to end.
Thank you so much for watching.
Good night!
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.